hi spring fans welcome to another
嗨，春季粉丝们欢迎来到另一个
installment of spring tips in this
在此安装Spring 提示
installment we're going to look at
我们将要看的分期付款
reactive views and what I mean by that
反应性观点，我的意思是
is we're going to look at regular HTTP
我们将要看常规的HTTP
but with an eye towards taking advantage
但着眼于利用
of reactive programming to build more
反应式编程以构建更多
interactive dynamic views and this isn't
交互式动态视图，这不是
something that we need to do I mean yeah
我们需要做的事情是的
I think you can gather from previous
我想你可以从以前
videos how to do some of what we're
视频如何做一些我们要做的事
going to talk about namely service in
要说的就是服务于
events and WebSockets but there's some
事件和WebSockets，但是有一些
more possibilities here and the reason I
这里更多的可能性以及我的原因
want to talk about all this is because I
想谈谈这一切是因为我
feel like there's a class of
感觉好像有一类
applications that exists where we'd like
我们想要的地方存在的应用程序
to have a little bit more dynamic
有一点动感
behavior on the page without having to
页面上的行为，而不必
completely go full client-side right and
完全使用完整的客户端权限，
so these are the these are sort of what
这些就是这些
I imagine is or I think of as
我想是或我认为是
departmental kind of applications there
部门部门的申请
are applications that are you know maybe
是您知道的应用程序
not as dynamic as Gmail right I mean
我不像Gmail那样动态
there's a lot of applications for which
有很多应用
this is true and and I think we've kind
这是真的，我认为我们很友善
of Manjula mess wing right at this point
Manjula乱翼的位置此时
I think it's fair to say that's
我认为可以公平地说
client-side programming JavaScript
客户端编程JavaScript
programming is vastly more complicated
编程要复杂得多
and anything I can I can ask you to do
我可以请你做的所有事情
in this on the server side with Java and
在Java的服务器端
spring right so so at this point there's
Spring 吧，所以在这一点上
this this you know just insane amount of
这个，你知道疯狂的数量
code that has to get generated and
必须生成的代码，以及
transpiled and compiled and you know all
转译和编译，你们都知道
that stuff just to be able to take
这些东西只是为了能够
advantage of projects like angular and
角度项目和项目的优势
react and I've even used angular and
反应，我什至使用角度和
there's a there's a nice library called
有一个很好的图书馆叫做
vu dat j/s which is nice as well I mean
vu dat j / s这也很好
a lot of good options out there and I'm
有很多不错的选择，我
a fan but if all you're trying to do is
粉丝，但如果您要做的是
to add a little bit of dynamic behavior
增加一点动态行为
to a page then that might be a bit
到页面，然后可能会有点
overkill especially if you don't have
过度杀伤，尤其是如果你没有
the skills and so in previous videos
之前视频中的技能等
I've talked about Vaadin for example
我说过Vaadin
that's a component model-based way of
这是基于组件模型的方式
generating markup and dom elements and
生成标记和dom元素，以及
pages and CSS and all that stuff all
页面和CSS以及所有这些东西
from within a swing you know the the UI
从一开始就知道UI
frameworks wing-like component model
框架翼状组件模型
that in turn trans piles into JavaScript
反过来反过来变成JavaScript
components right it's a very interesting
组件对，这非常有趣
approach you know it looks fine and I
方法，你知道它看起来不错，我
think that's okay if you we want more
认为还可以，如果我们想要更多
dynamic HTML and all that stuff but if
动态HTML和所有其他内容，但如果
you just want like a if you just have an
你只是想像一个，如果你只有一个
HTML page with good CSS and all that
具有良好CSS和其他所有功能的HTML页面
stuff and you just want to add some deny
东西，你只想添加一些否认
behavior
行为
you can get a lot done if you just know
只要知道就可以完成很多工作
a little bit of JavaScript and I think
一点JavaScript，我认为
this is easier for a lot of people than
对许多人来说，这比
going the opposite direction right I
我朝相反的方向走
suspect this is gonna be easier for
怀疑这会更容易
people like me who have a fair bit of
像我这样的人
skills on the server side but who aren't
服务器方面的技能，但不是
fluent in their clients I'd like my
我需要我的客户流利
friend Matt Mabel and so for these
朋友Matt Mabel等
people who are fluent or just native in
流利或刚出生的人
that client-side world and who don't
那个客户端世界，谁不
mind managing the ever sort of changing
处理不断变化的思想
landscape that is that world it's a
那就是那个世界的风景
natural thing to move to the client side
转移到客户端的自然选择
and as you use frameworks like react and
当您使用诸如react和
an angular they start to take over
他们开始占领一个角度
progressively more and more of the
越来越多的
things that get shown on the screen and
屏幕上显示的东西
so at that point spring becomes a very
所以在那一刻， Spring 变得非常
useful way to stand up HTTP services
站立HTTP服务的有用方法
right you have a you have WebSockets you
对，你有一个WebSockets你
have HTTP based API is REST API but you
具有基于HTTP的API是REST API，但是您
consume all that from the browser client
消耗浏览器客户端的所有内容
the client the JavaScript client and
客户端JavaScript客户端和
then you know if you start using angular
那你就知道你是否开始使用角
and react the work of actually rendering
并对实际渲染的工作做出反应
a view including the markup gets buried
包含标记的视图被掩埋
in the JavaScript code and of course
在JavaScript代码中，当然
this creates a very dynamic experience
这创造了非常动态的体验
but it means that you now have a thing
但这意味着你现在有一个东西
that is purely JavaScript all the CSS
纯粹是JavaScript的所有CSS
all the Dom elements all the HTML all
所有Dom元素所有HTML全部
the markup all that all they see
他们看到的所有标记
everything is actually just materialized
一切实际上都已实现
thanks to JavaScript code that runs on
多亏了运行的JavaScript代码
the it when the page loads which of
页面加载哪个时
course search engines can't necessarily
当然搜索引擎不一定
glom onto they can't sees what's
凝视着他们看不到什么
happening there they need the page
在那里发生他们需要页面
itself so they can index it and so
本身，以便他们可以对其进行索引等等
there's been a trend we have gone to we
有一种趋势，我们去了我们
see in the client-side world that people
在客户端世界中看到人们
are when when possible they take their
是什么时候他们采取他们的
their client-side renderer and use the
他们的客户端渲染器并使用
same thing on the server-side and these
在服务器端，这些
were so-called isomorphic applications
是所谓的同构应用
and these are I think these are kind of
这些是我认为这些是
interesting in and of themselves their
他们自己很有趣
applications that that render using
使用渲染的应用程序
static sort of templates on the server
服务器上的静态模板种类
side but then they're also built you
一边，但他们也造就了你
know they're also built in such a way
知道他们也是这样建造的
that the same template the same view is
相同的模板相同的视图是
being built on a client with exactly the
建立在具有完全
same inputs the same mark
相同输入相同标记
the same everything the same template
一样的东西都一样的模板
it's just that now it's being
只是现在
regenerated it's being updated on the
重新生成它正在更新
client and that's being used to pro to
客户，这是用来帮助
update the HTML page that's already been
更新已经存在的HTML页面
loaded so the effect is that you've got
加载，所以效果是你已经
this statically pre-rendered buffer of
此静态预渲染的缓冲区
strings that gets sent down from the
从
server to the client and that loads
服务器到客户端并加载
super fast there's no computation
超快速，无需计算
required to load the markup and then you
需要加载标记，然后您
have the same templating library the
具有相同的模板库
same view logic being used on a client
在客户端上使用相同的视图逻辑
to then render a JavaScript version of
然后呈现的JavaScript版本
that to to use JavaScript to then render
使用JavaScript然后呈现
a you know a series of Dom nodes that
你知道一系列的Dom节点
looks exactly the same as what you got
看起来和你得到的完全一样
when you rendered it on the server side
当您在服务器端渲染它时
and the benefit of course is that you
当然，好处是您
get really fast loads and then you can
得到非常快的负载，然后您就可以
progressively enhance these these pages
逐步增强这些页面
now that that only happens of course
现在那只会发生
when you offload all your views to
当您将所有视图卸载到
client-side JavaScript there's only
客户端JavaScript只有
requirement when you do that but if you
当您这样做时的要求，但如果您
have server-side views if you have
具有服务器端视图（如果有）
server-side templates and just want to
服务器端模板，只想
add some dynamic behavior it seems a
添加一些动态行为似乎
little little it seems a bridge too far
一点点，似乎一座桥太远了
for me to go all the way to the
让我一路走到
client-side and then try and get the
客户端，然后尝试获取
client side to have the same rendering
客户端具有相同的渲染
engine why not just use you know the
引擎为什么不仅仅使用您就知道了
server-side rendering engine to render
服务器端渲染引擎进行渲染
the page and then update the parts that
页面，然后更新
you care about and this is not a an old
你在乎，这不是一个老
idea of course I mean I'm you've you've
我当然是说你是你的意思
no doubt some of you will remember the
毫无疑问，你们中的一些人会记得
days before what we used to call Ajax
我们以前称Ajax的天数
right now we just call it you know HTTP
现在我们就称它为HTTP
requests that you can make from the
您可以从
browser but before we called it Ajax and
浏览器，但在我们将其称为Ajax和
before that in 2004 ish we talked about
在2004年之前，我们谈论过
something called dhtml and I think the
称为dhtml的东西，我认为
the distinction there was t HTML was
没有HTML的区别是
just sort of dynamic pages with no sort
只是动态页面，没有任何排序
of discussion or you know understanding
讨论或您了解
of how these pages were communicating
这些页面如何交流
with a back-end and it finally it became
与后端，它最终成为
possible for browser clients to make
浏览器客户端可以
calls to back-end services that is to
调用后端服务
say they were no longer constrained to
说他们不再受限于
their sandbox and this allowed them to
他们的沙盒，这使他们能够
drive the updates of the page from
从中驱动页面更新
information on the server and we call
服务器上的信息，我们致电
that Ajax and I think there's still a
那我和阿贾克斯（Ajax）还有一个
lot of applications for which Ajax that
Ajax的很多应用
that very simple model of you know
你知道的那个非常简单的模型
having a regular page that you update
有您要更新的常规页面
dynamically could be useful certainly if
动态地可能会有用，如果
you want to get something out of the box
你想开箱即用
up and running quick so what we're gonna
快速启动并运行，所以我们要
do is I'm gonna build a little
我要做的是建造一点
application and we're going to use the
应用程序，我们将使用
reactive web support here right so let's
反应式网络支持就在这里，让我们
say reactive
说反应性
views alright we're gonna use Lombok
好的意见，我们将使用龙目岛
we're gonna use the reactive web support
我们将使用反应式网络支持
and when use time leaf
以及何时使用时间叶
all right that's a server-side
好的，这是服务器端
templating engine I hit generate I'm
我命中的模板引擎生成我
gonna open this up here
要在这里打开
now we have a brand new application and
现在我们有了一个全新的应用程序，
we're just gonna sort of approach the
我们只是要采取某种方式
same problem a number of different ways
相同问题有多种不同的方式
first of all let's try ye olde sse okay
首先，让我们尝试一下
we're gonna create an SSE endpoint and
我们将创建一个SSE端点，
so all I'm gonna do I'm not gonna you
所以我要我做的不是你
know I've got I've done other videos on
知道我已经完成了其他视频
each of these things so I'm not gonna
这些东西中的每一个，所以我不会
linger too much on that what I'm gonna
在我要去的事情上流连忘返
do is I'm going to create a producer
我要做的就是创建一个制作人
that produces updates it's just gonna be
会产生更新
a publisher that produces updates every
每个发布者都会产生更新的发布者
let's say second okay and so it'll be a
让我们说第二个好吧，所以这将是一个
spring bean that produces update subtype
产生更新子类型的Spring bean
greetings okay
问候好
string message and publisher of greet
字符串消息和欢迎发布者
string name and we'll say flux done from
字符串名称，我们将说通量是从
stream stream that generate new supplier
产生新供应商的物流
and we're gonna say just return a new
我们要说的只是返回一个新
bleeding so and the green will have a
如此流血，绿色就会有
message and I'll give it a constructor
消息，我给它一个构造函数
alright there's that no work it's
好吧，那是没有工作的
constructor and we'll say I'm hello name
构造函数，我们会说我是名字
at will give it the time so they have an
会给它时间，所以他们有一个
idea when this is being done all right
想法什么时候完成的
good stuff that's a lambda very good and
好东西，这是一个很好的lambda，
of course I want to stagger that by
我当然想错开
introducing 1 second delay so we have a
引入1秒的延迟，所以我们有一个
hope of being able to follow it with her
希望能够跟着她
with the naked eye
肉眼
okay so that'll be a spring beam good so
好，那将是一个Spring 梁
that's our beam now we're gonna create a
这就是我们的光束，我们要创建一个
service and event view and this is we're
服务和事件视图，这是我们
just gonna create a service an event
只是要创建一个服务事件
stream s to see readings controller
流s查看读数控制器
alright and this controller it's just a
好了，这个控制器只是一个
regular spring MVC or spring web flex in
常规spring MVC或spring web flex in
this case we're using the reactive web
在这种情况下，我们使用反应式网络
support here and again what I've done is
一遍又一遍地支持我
I've created a stream that's gonna it's
我创建了一个流，它将
a value that will keep updating and so
一个会不断更新的值，因此
it'll keep producing new values and new
它将继续产生新的价值和新的
updates in perpetuity forever every one
永远永久更新
second so I'm gonna use that
第二个，所以我要用那个
create a of you here we're gonna say
在这里创建一个你的我们会说
create a view of ssee
创建ssee视图
greetings alright and you know what
好的问候，你知道吗
arguably we probably want the name I'm
可以说我们可能想要我的名字
not sure if it'll actually buy us
不确定是否会实际购买我们
anything so I'll get rid of that
任何东西，所以我会摆脱它
actually we can have the name why not
其实我们可以有一个名字为什么不
let's have a name so we'll keep the name
我们有一个名字，所以我们保留这个名字
and in the SC page we'll say name so
在SC页面中，我们会说出名字
we'll say publisher of greeting greet
我们会说问候的发行人打招呼
and we'll use that as a path variable
我们将其用作路径变量
string name alright and in order to do
字符串名称还可以，为了
this I'm going to inject the greetings
这我要打招呼
producer like so you can create the
像这样的制作人，您可以创建
constructor or you can start to do as
构造函数，或者您可以开始做为
I've been doing more often recently is
我最近常做的事是
just use mom bucks required articles
只需使用妈妈钱必要的文章
constructor I finally gave in it is just
我最终给出的构造函数只是
too simple not to not to do it okay so
太简单了，不要不这样做，所以
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna say when
我要做的是我要说什么时候
somebody calls this endpoint living at
有人称这个端点生活在
that endpoint we're gonna send back a
我们要发送的那个端点
content type of text event stream like
文本事件流的内容类型，例如
that and we'll say a producer dot greet
那，我们会说一个制作人点招呼
passing in the name the path variable
在名称中传递path变量
the name alright now how do we use that
这个名字好了，我们怎么使用
from a client well that's simple let's
从客户那里，很简单，让我们
just create a page here in the directory
只需在目录中创建一个页面
called static so we're gonna create a
叫做static，所以我们要创建一个
static assets directory spring but will
静态资产目录春季，但将
automatically serve anything in the
自动为
static directory to the client
客户端的静态目录
I'm going to call this ssee dot HTML and
我将其称为ssee点HTML和
we'll just write to am a smidge of
我们只是写信给
something that I'm not really proud of
我并不为之骄傲的事情
but hey you know I'm I do it for you
但嘿，你知道我是我为你做的
we're gonna write some JavaScript okay
我们要写一些JavaScript好的
so add event listener load function e
因此添加事件监听器加载功能e
and we're gonna have an update ID is
我们将有一个更新ID为
gonna be update and we're gonna say VAR
将要更新，我们要说VAR
e s equals new event source so HTTP
es等于新的事件源，因此HTTP
localhost 8080 and the endpoint we're
本地主机8080和端点
gonna call is this one here greetings
要打来的，这是这里的问候
names s SE greetings names and we have
名字s SE问候名字，我们有
to prompt it to provide a string for the
提示它为
for the name itself and so to do that
为名称本身，所以这样做
I'll ask for name I'll ask the user for
我要问名字我要问用户
a name to greet okay you should
一个可以打招呼的名字
great okay prompt past that end alright
很好，很快就过去了
and as events come in we're gonna use
随着事件的到来，我们将使用
the on message event to to then update
消息事件，然后更新
our dawn element and our dalam element
我们的黎明元素和我们的达兰元素
is update so I'm gonna say bar update
是更新，所以我要说吧更新
equals document dot get element by ID
等于ID的文档点获取元素
update will say update dot inner HTML
更新将显示更新点内部HTML
equals wouldn't want to do I want to say
等于不想做我想说
this plus message plus this all right a
这个加消息加上这个好吧
little bit of markup I I don't know I'm
一点点加价II不知道我是
not loving that maybe I could have
不爱也许我可以
actually had a nested element it could
实际上有一个嵌套的元素
have been h1 and then inside that I
一直是h1，然后在里面
could have updated that but you can
可能已经更新了，但是您可以
imagine for any kind of non-trivial
想象任何不平凡的
thing you know you might get more
你知道你可能会得到更多的东西
complex objects than just greetings
复杂的对象而不仅仅是问候
objects so you know you're gonna want to
对象，所以您知道您想要
take that data and then build the Dom
收集数据，然后建立Dom
tree around it dynamically right and so
动态围绕它的树等等
you can imagine how that would work
你可以想象这将如何工作
actually what I'm gonna get back in this
其实我要回去的
case the message data is gonna be a
如果消息数据将是一个
publish of reading so I don't really
发表阅读，所以我不是真的
want that do I
想要我吗
I just want names right how you know I
我只是想让名字正确，你怎么知道我
want the messages rather so I'll get
想要消息而不是我会得到
them message so I'm going to say greet
他们的消息，所以我要说问候
name map greeting get message so now I'm
名称地图问候得到消息，所以我现在
sending a publisher of strings back and
发回字符串的发布者，然后
at least that won't work correctly if I
至少如果我不能正常工作
put it in put it in between h1 it won't
把它放在h1之间就不会
be some sort of you know it won't be h1
是某种你知道不会是h1
than JSON representation of a greeting
比问候语的JSON表示形式
and then h1 it'll just be h1 and then
然后是h1就只是h1然后
the message
讯息
alright so buddy you can see you have to
好吧，哥们，你可以看到你必须
get both sides to agree on that ok let's
让双方都同意这一点，让我们
just try that out this is a spring boot
尝试一下，这是一个 spring boot
to it up to X application so I'll use
直到X应用程序，所以我将使用
Lee as the initialization one thing I
李作为初始化我的一件事
didn't do but which I should have done
没有做，但我应该做的
back on the initializer is to use the
回到初始化是使用
dev tools and so now with that done I
开发工具，所以现在完成了
can compile you start the application
可以编译您启动应用程序
alright
好的
that's up and running let's try that
启动并运行，让我们尝试一下
again get the shake off the first
再次摆脱第一
compile
编译
okay now we're cooking now it's up to
好吧，现在我们在做饭
speed a little bit so I've got an
加快一点，所以我有一个
applications up and running we're gonna
应用程序启动并运行
go see the page at SSC I'm sorry we call
请访问SSC上的页面，对不起，我们致电
it SSC tiniest amount right so SSC dot
它是SSC最小的数量，所以SSC点
HTML and we're gonna greet a spring fan
HTML，我们要迎接 Spring 的粉丝
Boop spring fans did I make a javascript
Boop Spring粉丝我做了JavaScript吗
error SSC 500 what
错误SSC 500什么
multi-value oh it's a rest controller
多值哦，这是一个 rest controller
friends it's a rest controller hmm I
朋友，这是一个 rest controller ，嗯，我
should know that you know I I can think
应该知道你知道我能想到
of a lot of people who know that I
很多人知道我
should be one of them
应该是其中之一
that's okay I'll just use dev tools to
没关系，我将使用开发工具
restart and there it is and we're gonna
重新启动，就可以了，我们要
say spring fans all right and there we
说 Spring 的粉丝们没事，我们在那里
go so every second it's gonna get a new
所以每一秒钟都会得到一个新的
update and we're updating this element
更新，我们正在更新此元素
on the client side and not so bad right
在客户端，还不错
the end the actual markup is being done
最后完成实际的标记
on the client we're actually modifying
在客户端上，我们实际上正在修改
the client this way all right that works
这样客户就可以了
fine I guess now another way to do this
好吧，我想现在是另一种方式
is to use WebSockets so let's do
是使用WebSockets，所以我们做
WebSockets will do WebSocket
WebSockets将做WebSocket
configuration and in a WebSocket code
配置和WebSocket代码中
it's just give me a configuration class
这只是给我一个配置类
and I'm gonna create a beam of simple
我将创造一束简单的光束
URL handler mapping and this is going to
URL处理程序映射，这将
be a thing that has information that
成为具有信息的东西
spring needs to know about spring web
Spring 需要了解Spring 网
flex needs to know about in order to
flex需要了解以便
properly mount to your endpoint for
正确安装到您的端点
consumption to the outside world okay so
消费到外面好吗
there's this mapped i/o and we'll say ws
有这个映射的I / O，我们会说ws
beans all right we need to provide a
bean 好吧，我们需要提供一个
WebSocket handler the WebSocket handler
WebSocket处理程序WebSocket处理程序
we're going to define a minute that our
我们将定义一个分钟，
business logic lives but we need that
业务逻辑存在，但我们需要
okay so map of wsh all right
好的，所以wsh的地图还可以
why are you upset
你为什么不高兴
set your on that
设置你的
well
好
oh I forgot to update this to 11 that's
哦，我忘了将此更新为11
why all right so maven import ok there
为什么还行，所以行家在那里可以导入
we go I'm I am losing my mind clearly
我们走了，我正在清楚地失去理智
but at least I was able to figure this
但至少我能弄清楚
out now we need a a WebSocket Handler
现在我们需要一个WebSocket处理程序
adapter ok so and we need funny the
适配器好吧，我们需要有趣的
WebSocket handler which is our business
WebSocket处理程序是我们的业务
object this is the thing that we're
反对，这就是我们要做的事情
going to create that actually produces
要创造出真正产生的
the response the stream basically in
流的响应基本上在
order to do that we're going to create
为了做到这一点，我们将要创建
our greetings we're going to inject our
我们的问候，我们要注入我们的
greetings producer and use that to
问候制作人并将其用于
define this WebSocket handler ok so the
定义此WebSocket处理程序，这样
job of website can enter is very simple
网站的工作可以进入很简单
when the client the JavaScript client
当客户端JavaScript客户端
connects to the server there's an
连接到服务器，有一个
exchange that goes on an upgrade from
从进行升级的交易所
HTTP to to WebSockets and then finally a
HTTP到WebSockets，最后
session is created and then then that's
会话被创建，然后
when we get involved the server gives us
当我们参与其中时，服务器会给我们
a reference to the session and we can
会话参考，我们可以
use that to say ok what did the client
用这个说好，客户做了什么
send to us so let's receive the data
发送给我们，让我们接收数据
what we get is a publisher of WebSocket
我们得到的是WebSocket的发布者
message and for each WebSocket message I
消息，对于每个WebSocket消息，我
want to unpack the message and get the
想要打开邮件包装并获取
text and that's actually a publisher of
文字，实际上是
names to greet well of course there's
名字打招呼当然有
only gonna be one value but it's still a
只会是一个价值，但仍然是
publisher right now what I want to do I
发布商现在要做什么
want to take that names to greet and
想以这个名字来问候
turn it into a stream of what of
把它变成
greetings right to send back to the
问候权发回
client an updated stream of readings so
客户更新了阅读数据流，因此
I'm going to say names to greet dot
我要说名字打招呼
flatmap taking in the name to greet in
平面图以要问候的名称
question and using producer to greet
问题并使用生产者打招呼
that name to greet and that's gonna give
要打招呼的那个名字
me a publisher of greetings ok response
我是问候的发布者，好的回复
readings alright now that's that's good
好了，现在读数很好
but I'm actually I actually want the
但是我实际上我真的想要
text of that so I'm going to say
该文本，所以我要说
response readings that map g gr dot get
映射g gr dot得到的响应读数
message alright and that'll give me a
好消息，那会给我一个
string of string responses all right and
正确的字符串响应字符串，
finally from there what I want to do is
最终从那里我想做的是
I want to send that as a series of text
我想将其作为一系列文本发送
messages that is to say not like an SMS
表示不像短信的消息
but like a like a WebSocket text message
但是就像WebSocket短信一样
so we say string responses map string
所以我们说字符串响应映射字符串
greeting session about text message
关于短信的问候会议
passing in that and that gives us a
通过，那给了我们一个
publisher of WebSocket message which we
我们发布的WebSocket消息的发布者
can send back to the client
可以发回给客户
like this okay now all together now how
这样好吧，现在都在一起怎么
do we you know what do we normally do
您知道我们通常会做什么吗
well first of all clean that up get rid
首先要清理干净
of the intermediate variables because
的中间变量，因为
they add nothing here okay good stuff so
他们没有在这里添加任何东西，好东西，所以
there's our readings publisher what
有我们的阅读出版商
we're doing is we're saying we seed the
我们正在做的是说我们播种了
data map it turn it in to a publisher
数据映射将其交给发布者
etc it's actually very elegant if you
等等，如果你真的很优雅
think about it I kind of like it
考虑一下，我有点喜欢
actually how would you like it and of
其实你想要什么以及
course this can be a lambda as well so
当然这也可以是lambda，所以
there's our our whole WebSocket based
这是我们基于整个WebSocket的
application that takes input and
需要输入和
responds to output there is no path
响应输出没有路径
variables here obviously there's no path
这里的变量显然没有路径
variables for the WebSocket endpoint but
WebSocket端点的变量，但
that's okay because we can you know
没关系，因为我们可以知道
server-sent events are a unidirectional
服务器发送的事件是单向的
communication protocol WebSockets are
通信协议WebSockets是
bi-directional so I can just I can just
双向的，所以我可以
send data from the WebSocket client get
从WebSocket客户端发送数据获取
the data in respond to it and so on
响应数据等等
alright so with that we've got our
好吧，有了它，我们有了
WebSocket handler now we need a page so
WebSocket处理程序现在我们需要一个页面，因此
let's create a new file here that HTML
让我们在此处创建一个新文件
HTML body script and then you know
HTML主体脚本，然后您就会知道
basically the same structure as SSE
与上证所基本相同
actually if you think about it so I'm
实际上，如果您考虑一下，那么我
gonna do this but some things are
要这样做，但有些事情是
different first of all we've got to do
首先我们要做的是不同的
update element that's fine right we had
更新元素，我们没事的
that before we want the name to greet
在我们想要名字之前
but we're not using this we're not using
但我们没有使用我们没有使用
event source we're using web socket so
我们使用网络套接字的事件源
web socket and the endpoint that we're
Web套接字和我们的端点
gonna call is here it's called ws
要打电话到这里叫ws
readings so we go back to our web socket
阅读，所以我们回到网络插座
code and it's not HTTP here it's WS
代码，不是HTTP，这里是WS
that's a new protocol right it's the
这是一个新的协议，对
different protocol um and we don't need
不同的协议，我们不需要
the name so now we have okay so now we
这个名字，所以现在我们可以了，所以现在我们
need to get the data we need to get the
需要获取数据，我们需要获取
name to greet in order to do that I'm
为了迎接我而打招呼的名字
going to ask a question when I say when
我说什么时候要问一个问题
this socket is opened let's send a
这个插座打开了，让我们发送一个
request let's say WS send
要求说WS发送
this name right the name that we've
这个名字对我们已经拥有的名字
prompted for and then when the data
提示然后输入数据
comes back on the on message column
回到“消息上”列
that's exactly the same as before when
那和以前的时候完全一样
that comes back then we'll update the
回来，然后我们将更新
HTML using message data and the same
HTML与消息数据相同
thing applies right for our WebSocket
事情适用于我们的WebSocket
code we're just sending strings we're
我们只是发送字符串的代码
not sending the JSON we could but we
我们不发送JSON，但是我们
don't need to alright so now we can do
不需要好，所以现在我们可以做
this okay so that's ws dead HTML here
这样就好了，这里的HTML已经死了
you are spring you know spring WebSocket
你是 Spring ，你知道 Spring WebSocket
fans okay
粉丝们好
so totally different technology we're
所以我们是完全不同的技术
now using interactive bi-directional web
现在使用交互式双向网络
socket API is but we're getting the same
套接字API是，但是我们得到了相同的结果
effect you can see that this is updating
效果，您可以看到它正在更新
at roughly every second tonight we're
今晚大约每隔一秒钟
sending back down that data back to the
将数据向下发送回
client and this is live all right this
客户，这是活的好吧
is that's the thing that's the reason
就是这个原因
you would care about these kinds of
你会关心这些
things is liveliness what if I have chat
事情很活泼，如果我聊天
messages or stock tickers or a clock in
消息或股票行情自动收录器或时钟
this case a ticking clock which has a
这种情况下的滴答钟
friendly message or something like that
友好的信息或类似的东西
whatever right anything you can imagine
随便你能想像什么
being updated all the time and again I I
一直在不断更新II
staggered the results by one second but
将结果错开一秒钟，但
there's no reason it couldn't be a new
没有理由不能成为新事物
value every nanosecond I mean assuming
我假设每纳秒就值
your browser doesn't mind creating Dom
您的浏览器不介意创建Dom
nodes and destroying them that quickly
节点并迅速摧毁它们
and by the way if they do care about
顺便说一句，如果他们确实关心
that that's a good reason for you to
那是你的好理由
care about things like react which
关心诸如反应之类的事情
actually creates a virtual DOM and can
实际上创建了一个虚拟DOM，并且可以
minimize garbage collection for for
尽量减少垃圾收集
objects created in the Dom itself
在Dom本身中创建的对象
because that's not not cheap but um okay
因为那不便宜，但是嗯
so we've got this now I in this case I
所以我们现在有了这个
end up getting into the business of
最终涉足
creating HTML markup and it's pretty
创建HTML标记，这很漂亮
easy to get away with some amazing
容易摆脱一些惊人的
things if you're using you know updated
如果您正在使用，知道更新
inner HTML I remember a time when inner
内部HTML我记得当内部HTML
HTML wasn't supported and all in all
不支持HTML
browsers and so in order to to update
浏览器等以便更新
the Dom you'd actually have to create
您实际上必须创建的Dom
Dom elements you'd say document create
您会说文档创建的Dom元素
element and then you'd get a node and
元素，然后您将获得一个节点和
then you design attributes to it then
然后你为它设计属性
you'd append it to a parent node you
您可以将其附加到父节点上
know you ended up doing a lot of builder
知道你最终做了很多建设者
code in JavaScript just to modify the
JavaScript中的代码只是为了修改
Dom because you couldn't trust you
Dom因为你不信任你
HTML to work consistently those days are
在那些日子里，HTML能够持续工作
long since passed for the very large
很久以前就过去了
majority of us but that said you will
我们大多数人，但是那说明你会
you know you will probably find yourself
你知道你可能会发现自己
in some situation where you're doing
在某些情况下，您正在做
things to the Dom to modify it and to
到Dom修改它并
get a user interface going inside of
进入用户界面
JavaScript code and I don't wanna
JavaScript代码，我不想
I just don't I'm I'd rather go to
我只是不，我宁愿去
production so one interesting
生产如此有趣
opportunity here is a feature that's
这里的机会是
unique in time leaf which supports
在时间上独特的支持
reactive sort of server sent event
服务器发送事件的反应式
updated views so what we're gonna do is
更新视图，所以我们要做的是
we're gonna create a time leaf view
我们将创建一个时间叶子视图
controller okay it's gonna be a timely
管制员好吧，这将是及时的
view readings controller and what this
查看读数控制器，这是什么
is gonna do it's going to be a regular
要去做，这将是一个常规
controller not a rest controller it's
控制器不是 rest controller
gonna load you know in greetings page it
会在问候页面中加载您知道的内容
could be anything
可以是任何东西
greetings dot JSP greetings dot you know
问候点JSP问候点您知道
PHP don't do that or view whatever or
PHP不这样做，也不查看任何内容，或者
you might remember the old struts
您可能还记得旧的支柱
do right I'm gonna render the initial
对吧，我要渲染首字母
view here and all that's gonna do is
在这里查看，所有要做的就是
it's gonna render a greetings HTML
它会呈现问候语HTML
template and this is a time Nick
模板，这是尼克的时间
template now time leaf is a server-side
现在，模板时间叶是服务器端
framework it's a server-side rendering
框架是服务器端渲染
engine rather a templating engine that
引擎而不是模板引擎
you can use to render pages so we're
您可以用来呈现页面，所以我们
gonna create a new folder here spring
Spring 会在这里创建一个新文件夹
boot will automatically render or make
开机会自动渲染或制作
available it'll mount to all the views
可用它将安装到所有视图
that are in source main resources
在源主要资源中
templates it'll auto configure those as
模板，它将自动配置为
being part of the views if it finds a
如果发现一个
templating engine like timely for
像及时模板引擎
velocity or free marker or whatever on
速度或自由标记或其他任何东西
the path mat so there's static there's
路径垫，所以有静态的
templates and we're gonna create a new
模板，我们将创建一个新的
view here called greetings about HTML
在这里查看有关HTML的问候
now this is a page whose contents will
现在这是一个页面，其内容将
be updated by the server-side right
由服务器端权限更新
it'll actually be parsed by the server
它实际上将由服务器解析
side and then pre-processed like JSP but
然后像JSP一样预处理
with much more elegance and speed okay
更优雅，更快捷
and no inline Java code so what we're
而且没有内联Java代码，所以我们
doing is we're gonna say ID equals
我们要做的是说ID等于
greetings block okay
问候阻止好吗
and then inside this I'm going to visit
然后在里面我要去参观
each record in a pub and a stream of
酒吧中的每条记录以及
data okay so I'm going to use an
数据还可以，所以我将使用
attribute in four time leaf so for each
四个时间片中的属性
reading in the greetings attributes or
阅读问候属性或
attribute the model attribute just
仅仅赋予模型属性
render that string greeting okay there
在那里呈现该字符串的问候
you are and that's it that's my markup I
你是，那就是我的标记
do need a little bit of jump skipped oh
确实需要跳一点点哦
I should put that inside the body that's
我应该把它放在体内
important
重要
oh it is anybody yeah okay that's fine
哦，是任何人都可以，很好
so that would not I want some markup but
这样我就不需要加价了
what I'm what's important here is that
我最重要的是
I'm gonna keep this like all I'm gonna
我要像我要保持的一样
do is I'm gonna send a text message and
我要做的是发送短信，
yet I'll still keep the styling right
但我仍然会保持样式正确
else I can still I'm not gonna modify
否则我仍然可以修改
any that in code so I did color right
代码中的任何内容，所以我的颜色正确
color you know red or whatever royal
颜色你知道红色或任何皇家
blue green right okay so there's a green
蓝绿色好吧，所以有一个绿色
green okay
绿色还可以
so now I've got I've got the markup on
所以现在我有了标记
the in the template itself not in the
模板本身中没有
server-side all I'm gonna send is just a
我要发送的服务器端只是
regular text body and you can imagine
常规文本正文，您可以想象
how this would render the first time
这将如何呈现第一次
this would render if you ever seen time
如果您见过时间，这将呈现
time leaf or any other sort of view
时间片或任何其他类型的视图
templating engine I've created a model
我创建了模型的模板引擎
attribute here and that's gonna be
属性在这里，那将是
loaded into memory on the producer side
加载到生产者端的内存中
on the server and then the server is
在服务器上，然后服务器是
gonna take this template it's gonna
将采用此模板
merge the model attributes in the
合并模型属性
template with the model elements in the
带有模型元素的模板
model which is just a glorified map it's
模型只是一张美化的地图
a dictionary basically on the server
基本上在服务器上的字典
side and it's gonna say evaluate the
一边，它会说评估
contents of that well you know what what
那东西的内容，你知道什么
is the template meaning in context or in
是上下文中的模板含义
the in light of that data in the model
根据模型中的数据
and it's gonna render it out into a
它会把它渲染成一个
string buffer and it's gonna send that
字符串缓冲区，它将发送给
directly to the client well of course we
直接给客户当然，我们
can't do that here
在这里不能做到这一点
right we have a view whose data is gonna
对了，我们有一个视图，其数据将
be fed by this thing that's gonna
被这个东西吃饱了
produce new values forever
永远产生新的价值
so we can't wait for the end we can't
所以我们不能等到结局
exhaust the greetings model attribute
用尽问候模型属性
just to render this page so what we want
只是为了呈现此页面，所以我们想要
is a nice feature in time leaf that
是时间片的一个不错的功能
allows us to do service and event views
允许我们进行服务和事件视图
which i think is super cool so we do
我认为这很酷，所以我们
need to
需要
a little bit of code we save window dot
一点点代码，我们保存了窗口点
add eventlistener load function and VAR
添加eventlistener加载函数和VAR
e s equals new event source and what
es等于新的事件源以及什么
we're gonna do I'm going to connect to
我们要去连接
another event source here on the timely
另一个事件源在这里及时
few endpoint so locate this one we're
端点少，所以找到这个端点
gonna say value equals readings view
要说价值等于阅读观点
that do okay and we're next we're gonna
没关系，我们接下来是
expect a a query parameter okay and then
期望查询参数可以，然后
the the produces the service it'll be a
产生的服务将是一个
service an event stream like so but
像这样服务于事件流，但是
we're gonna render a page render updated
我们将渲染页面渲染更新
view so the client will actually look at
查看，以便客户实际查看
this so when a call we're gonna render a
因此，在通话时，我们将呈现一个
Sweeney's a special syntax here render
Sweeney是这里的一种特殊语法
the template called beatings but in
该模板称为殴打，但在
particular render this block not the
特别渲染该块而不是
whole thing just this block it's gonna
整个东西就是这个块
re-evaluate that block in order to do
重新评估该区块以进行
that you have to have time to write
你必须有时间写
you're using timely clear so I'm gonna
您正在使用及时清除，所以我要
create a model attribute and it's gonna
创建一个模型属性，它将
be in a model attribute for this
为此在模型属性中
attribute here of greetings and the
这里的问候和
greetings itself will be data from my
问候本身就是我的数据
publisher so readings equals and will
出版商，所以阅读等于并且会
inject the greetings producer good stuff
注入问候制作人的好东西
this step producer dot greet and of
这一步制片人打招呼和
course we need the view we need the name
当然我们需要视图我们需要名称
so I'll express a request pram here
所以我在这里表达一个要求
strange name so it'll be it'll be you
奇怪的名字，它将是你
know dollar sign it sorry question mark
知道美元符号对不起问号
name equals and then something and we'll
名称等于然后是某些东西，我们将
inject that there so I'm gonna pass that
注入那里，所以我要通过
in and that'll give us a string of of
在这将给我们带来一连串的
elements right and actually in this case
元素正确，实际上在这种情况下
because I have that because I'm I'm just
因为我拥有，因为我就是
using standard server-side generated
使用标准的服务器端生成
things I can actually render the message
我实际上可以呈现消息的东西
here I can actually say greeting this
在这里我真的可以说问候
dot what did we call it
点我们叫它什么
greetings producer greeting message so I
问候制作人问候消息，所以我
think we can just do that we could just
认为我们可以做到，我们可以做到
say greetings dot message
说问候点消息
okay and that'll do you reference the
好的，那您会参考
element on the server side least it
服务器端的元素最少
should appreciate well so we have this
应该很好，所以我们有这个
end point okay it's a stream in order to
终点好吧，这是一个流，以
create that data there we go we're
在我们那里创建数据
actually okay with that okay so that's
其实还可以，所以
what our client is gonna do is it's
我们的客户要做的是
going to call this from the event source
要从事件源调用
so localhost 8080 like that let's go say
所以像这样的localhost 8080
es add event listener load and we're
es添加事件侦听器负载，我们
sorry message function e I'm gonna say
抱歉，留言功能e我要说的是
message dot data that stage that's the
消息点数据的阶段是
mark up the service you know they
标记您知道的服务
updated markup and we're just gonna say
更新了标记，我们只是要说
let's update that update block okay so
让我们更新该更新块，好吧
update block equals document dot get
更新块等于文档点获取
element by ID readings block I'm gonna
通过ID读取来阻止的元素
say update block inner HTML equals the
说更新块内部HTML等于
data all right
数据还可以
so I'm basically I'm telling the server
所以我基本上是在告诉服务器
side
侧
hey process this block of text this is
嘿，处理这段文字是
this HTML on the server side you know
您知道服务器端的此HTML
evaluate it in context with this
以此来评估它
template and then send that back to the
模板，然后将其发送回
client well of course that the template
客户当然也知道模板
on the server side is going to have this
在服务器端将有这个
reactive stream of data and of course I
反应性数据流，当然我
want to send that back to the clients I
想要发回给我的客户
can't actually use a regular publisher I
我实际上不能使用常规发行商
almost got away with it I forgot to
我几乎忘了
changes I have to have a variable which
变化，我必须有一个变量
is a new reactant this is where the
是新的反应物，这是
magic happens like this and sew it up
魔术就这样发生并缝起来
says what that's going to do is it's
说这将要做的是
gonna read it we agree about this fact
要读它，我们同意这个事实
in reactive stream after one element has
一个元素具有
been emitted sitting this is the buffer
坐在这是缓冲区发出
okay so I'll say variable and I'll add
好吧，我将说变量，然后添加
that there and that's what that's what
那就是那就是那
actually allows us to work so it's a
实际上允许我们工作，所以这是一个
server-side view I'm returning a string
服务器端视图，我返回一个字符串
to resolve the view and yet it's a
解决视图，但这是一个
service an event stream right you saw me
服务一个事件流，就在您看到我时
do that before with a more like HTTP
之前使用更像HTTP的方法
service API but this is a view it's very
服务API，但这是一种观点
different and hmm that should just work
不同和嗯，应该工作
it now let's see I've got everything in
现在让我们看看我已经拥有了一切
place I've got the template greetings
我有模板问候的地方
that HTML it's going to render that when
该HTML将在何时呈现
you go to the timely few configuration
你去及时一些配置
it's gonna go to greetings do or we're
要去问候吗，否则我们
gonna call this greetings updates okay
会叫这个问候更新好吗
we're gonna go to our page here updates
我们要去我们的页面这里更新
all right let's uh restart that okay
好吧，让我们重新开始吧
good stuff so what do we call this we
好东西，所以我们怎么称呼我们
called this that's WS we don't want that
称之为WS，我们不想要那个
one we want the beatings do I think
我想一个人殴打我
right time leaf greetings do Oh
正确的时间叶问候做哦
greetings updates do 400 100 what's the
问候更新会显示400100，这是什么
error oh I need a parameter name equals
错误哦，我需要一个参数名称等于
uh spring fans is that not 400 bad
嗯， Spring 的粉丝不是400坏吗
request greetings do
请求问候吗
rendering the view called greetings
渲染称为问候的视图
that's this right here
就在这里
and let's just try restarting it just
让我们尝试重新启动它
for the heck of it what is the issue
到底是什么问题
here friend's name is not present I
这里没有朋友的名字我
think it it is I think it is
认为是我认为
oh this well no that's not right okay so
哦，好吧，不，那不好吧，所以
we're let's try it again that's a good
我们再试一次，那是一个很好的选择
point we do need that in the update
点，我们确实需要更新
endpoint don't we yeah yeah we needed
端点，不是吗，是的，我们需要
here okay so where do we get that let's
在这里好，那我们从哪里得到的
try that again so here in our JavaScript
再试一次，所以在我们的JavaScript中
code in the greetings template we need
我们需要的问候模板中的代码
to say name equals and then give it a
说名字等于然后给它一个
name so VAR name equals windows dot
名称，因此VAR名称等于Windows点
prompt a window prompt who should we
提示窗口提示我们应该给谁
greet all right same thing as before and
和以前一样打招呼，然后
obviously you would do better to it
显然你会做得更好
strong code or you all encode these
强大的代码，或者你们都编码这些
variables but hashtag Yolo okay and okay
变量，但是标签标签Yolo可以，也可以
command of nine
九点命令
I don't know if it started let's try
我不知道它是否开始让我们尝试
that again just restart okay there we go
再次重启就可以了
so spring them go on and you can see
所以 Spring 他们继续，你可以看到
what's happening over the network so
网络上发生了什么
here's the request and the response
这是请求和响应
query string and we're getting text
查询字符串，我们正在获取文本
event stream and the stream that's
事件流和
coming back is actually the mark-up
回来实际上是加价
itself as rendered on the server side so
本身呈现在服务器端，因此
you could do artificially complex
你可以人为地做
business logic on the server side you
服务器端的业务逻辑
could you know you could render out
你知道你可以渲染出来吗
objects and you know you can see it says
对象，你知道你可以看到它说
hello spring demand ID reference the
你好春季需求ID参考
name but the client side has no idea
名称，但客户端不知道
about the structure of the JSON object
关于JSON对象的结构
it's only ever on the server side that
只有在服务器端
we that we dereference Ted property and
我们取消引用Ted属性，并且
then load it into the template right so
然后将其加载到模板中，这样
you're not you're not exposing any of
你不是，你没有暴露任何
the JavaScript you're not JSON applying
您不是JSON的JavaScript
your objects only to then use them and
您的对象只是然后使用它们
building up the markup for here for the
为这里建立标记
elements in the in the Dom so I think
在大教堂的元素，所以我认为
it's a pretty cool feature good job time
这是一个很酷的功能，很好的工作时间
leaf I like that that's actually very
叶我喜欢那实际上是非常
nice and you can imagine stock tickers
很好，你可以想象股票行情
and chat messages and whatever you know
和聊天消息以及您所知道的
a lot of things that might be easier if
很多事情可能会更容易
you could just turn it into a stream
你可以把它变成流
like that I'm sure there's other things
像那样，我确定还有其他事情
you could do that are interesting like
你可以做的很有趣
this other it's possible to get this
这有可能得到这个
kind of effect kind of with with a thing
有点效果
that dr. Dave sire is working on and or
那位博士Dave父亲正在研究and或
had working at one point for free marker
曾经为免费标记工作过一点
I think I'm not sure if that's anywhere
我想我不确定那个地方
in any kind of project but if you ping
在任何项目中，但如果您ping
me I'll be able to find it and maybe you
我，我就能找到它，也许你
can brush it off or share it with people
可以刷掉它或与人分享
or I can point you in to the right right
或者我可以将您指向右边
direction either way good stuff I hope
我希望任何一种方式都可以
you enjoyed this and as always thanks so
您喜欢这个，一如既往的感谢
much for watching and we'll we'll see
值得观看，我们将拭目以待
you next time
下次你
you
您